if you're looking in your Bibles tonight
如果你今晚看你的圣经
and we hope to look in a whole lot of
我们希望看到很多
sections of the Bible tonight you'll
今晚圣经的哪些部分你会
find in Romans chapter 15 and in verse 4
在罗马书第15章和第4节中找到
Paul says this for whatever was written
无论写什么， 保罗说这都是
in earlier times was written for our
在早些时候是为我们写的
instruction so that through perseverance
指导， 以便通过坚持不懈
and the encouragement of the scriptures
以及经文的鼓励
we might find hope
我们可能会找到希望
why was the Old Testament written so
为什么旧约圣经如此写成
that you and I might have hope you can
你和我可能希望你能
be thrown into a pit by your brothers
被你兄弟扔进坑里
now talk about sibling rivalry you know
现在谈谈你知道的兄弟竞争
he got a nicer cold okay and he had this
他有一个更好的冷，他有这个
dream and in his dream all of his
梦想和他梦想中的所有
brothers Bob down to him and they got
兄弟鲍勃对他说，他们得到了
really upset with him and so they threw
他真的很不高兴，所以他们扔了
him in a pit first they were gonna kill
他在一个坑第一，他们会杀了
him then they said no that's like some
他然后他们说不是那样的
will make some money off this and we'll
会赚到一些钱，我们会
will sell him into slavery
将他卖给奴隶
now that's sibling rivalry to a great
现在这是一个伟大的兄弟姐妹的竞争
extent but Joseph continued to walk with
但是约瑟夫继续走路
God why he had hope how do we know that
上帝为什么他有希望我们怎么知道
because in the end of Genesis in chapter
因为在创世记的最后一章
50 he tells us when his brothers are
50他告诉我们他兄弟的时间
again concerned now dad has died and
再次关注现在爸爸已经死了
they're thinking well maybe he only was
他们思考得很好也许他只是
nice to us while Dad was living and now
爸爸生活的时候对我们很好
he's really gonna give the axe to us
他真的会给 我们斧头
because of what we did to him before and
由于我们 之前对他做和
so what Joseph said to them is what you
那么约瑟夫对他们所说的就是你
meant for evil God meant for good so
意味着邪恶上帝意味着好
there is hope in every single situation
每一种情况都有希望
that we face in life so as we're looking
我们正在寻找生活中所面对的
at this you've got real reasons they
在这，你有他们真正的理由
give genuine hope to every believer and
给每一个信徒和真正的希望
you're able to give genuine hope why
你能够给出真正的希望
well first of all because you have a
首先，因为你有一个
confident hope of eternal life that
永生的信心， 希望
confident hope of eternal life is found
找到了永生的自信希望
in Colossians 1:28 where he says
在歌罗西书1:28中，他说
Christ's Paul says Christ in you the
基督的保罗说基督在你里面
hope of glory Christ lives in you and
荣耀基督的希望住在你们和
that gives you confident hope it gives
这给了你自信的希望
you a hope in glory and then in
你是一个荣耀的希望 ，然后是
Galatians chapter 2 and verse 20 and 21
加拉太书第2章和 第20节和第21节
the Apostle Paul tells us there that the
使徒保罗告诉我们那里 的
life you now live in Christ you no
你现在生活在基督里的生活你没有
longer live in your own strength but you
长住在你自己的力量，但你
live it in the strength of Christ who
以基督的力量生活
lives within you it's not you who live
住在你里面，不是你的生活
not me who lives any longer buts Christ
不再是我的生活，而是基督
living in me any of you ever see the
生活在我身上的任何一个人都曾经看过
Incredible Hulk
不可思议的绿巨人
don't get him mad because when he gets
不要让他生气， 因为他得到了
mad
狂
somehow this chemical reaction happens
不知何故发生这种化学反应
inside of him and you know he is ready
他内心，你知道他已经准备好了
to tear you apart you don't want to mess
撕裂你，你不想乱
with him listen you don't want to mess
他听你 不想惹
with me because in me lives Christ
和我在一起，因为在我里面生活着
Christ in you the hope of glory he's
基督在你们的荣耀，希望他
living in you he gives you the power to
住在你，他给你的力量
do the will of God he gives you the will
按照上帝的旨意，他会赐给你意志
to do the will of God he's living in you
要遵行上帝的旨意，他就住在你里面
right now and so the world doesn't want
现在，所以世界不想要
to really mess with us Christ also gives
要真正惹恼我们，基督也给予了
us life in Romans chapter 8 and verses 8
我们生活在罗马书第8章和第8节
through 11 it talks about the spirit
到了11，它谈到了精神
living in us and giving us life and so
生活在我们身边，给我们生命
we live in the power and the strength of
我们生活在力量和力量之中
the Holy Spirit who lives within us and
圣灵在我们和谁住
then Christ has redeemed you for all of
然后基督赎回了你们所有人
eternity in Ephesians chapter one 13 and
以弗所书第一章第13章和第12章
14 it says that you have been redeemed
14它说你已被赎回
you have been bought back you have been
你被买了回来了
bought out of the slave market where you
从你所在的奴隶市场买走
were a slave to sin and you couldn't
是罪的奴隶，你不能
help yourself and you have now eternal
帮助自己，你现在永远
life in Christ you have been redeemed
在基督里的生活，你已经被救赎了
and you stand as a son of God Jesus came
和你站在上帝耶稣的儿子 来了
to pay the debt that you owed because
支付你所欠的债务，因为
you owed a debt that you couldn't pay
你欠下的债，你可以不支付
and he redeemed you from the marketplace
他把你从市场上救了出来
of sin and then also not only are you
罪恶，然后不仅是你
redeemed but in that scripture it tells
赎回但是在那经文中它说明了
you you are also sealed with the Holy
你也是神圣的封印
Spirit
精神
I wear a wedding ring and that wedding
我戴着结婚戒指和那场婚礼
ring says that I am set apart completely
戒指说我完全分开了
to one woman marry my wife and it's a
一个女人娶了我的妻子，这是一个
sign it's a symbol and the Holy Spirit
签下它是象征和圣灵
lives within you he's the seal he's the
生活在你的内心，他是他的密封
wedding ring which says that you have
婚戒它说，你有
been put together with Christ and he's
与基督和他一起被放在一起
going to finish that work he still
他还在完成这项工作
and completes you until the day of
并完成你直到那一天
Christ then Christ gives you a Living
基督然后基督给你一个生命
Hope through his resurrection if you
希望通过他的复活，如果你
look at the passage in 1st Peter in in
看看第一彼得的通道
chapter one there and that epistle the
第一章那里和那封书信
the Apostle and we have to keep those
使徒，我们必须保留这些
words straight he gives us this thought
直言不讳他给了我们这个想法
blessed be the God and father of our
祝福我们的上帝和父亲
Lord Jesus Christ who according to his
根据他的主耶稣基督
great mercy has caused us to be born
伟大的怜悯使我们出生
again to a Living Hope through the
再次通过生活希望
resurrection of Jesus Christ from the
从 耶稣基督复活
dead to obtain an inheritance which is
为了获得继承而去世
imperishable and undefiled and will not
不朽的，不玷污的，不会的
fade away
消逝
remember greek was all written in little
记得希腊语都写得很少
letters you know no capital letters and
你不知道大写字母和
it was all written together so the words
这一切都是一起写的
weren't separated and so you had what
没有分开，所以你有什么
did you I mean Peters computer didn't
你是不是我的意思是彼得斯电脑没有
have highlight put this in italics you
有突出表明用斜体字表示你
can underline this you can put it all in
可以强调这一点，你可以把它全部放进去
capitals he couldn't do that so when
资本， 他不能这样做的时候
they're writing and Greek what they do
他们写作和希腊语他们做什么
it they wanted you to get the point they
他们希望你能得到他们的观点
piled words together look at the words
堆起来的话一起看看这些话
pile together blessed be the God and
堆在一起祝福是上帝和
father of our Lord Jesus Christ who
我们的主耶稣基督的父亲
according to his great mercy has caused
根据他的伟大怜悯造成的
us to be born again to a Living Hope
我们重生于活着的希望
through the resurrection of Jesus Christ
通过耶稣基督的复活
from the dead to obtain an inheritance
从死者那里获得遗产
which is imperishable and undefiled and
这是不朽的和无瑕疵的
will not fade away reserved in heaven
不会在天堂中消失
for you well you ought to get excited
对你而言， 你应该感到兴奋
that let me not there any Baptists here
这让我没有任何浸礼会教友
shouting amen I mean what what is this
喊着阿门我的意思是这是什么
man I know it's Friday nights been a
我知道这是周五晚上的一个人
long week ok that's why you need hope so
长周好，这就是你需要希望的原因
let's keep going
让我们继续前进
who are protected by the power of God
谁受上帝的力量保护
through faith for a salvation ready to
通过信仰准备救赎
be revealed in the last time you are
在你最后一次是被揭示
safe you are in Christ and you have a
安全的你在基督里，你有一个
hope that goes them beyond the grave on
希望超越坟墓
the way down here I was talking to my
在这里，我正在和我说话
sister on my cell phone and I learned
姐姐在我的手机上，我学到了
that my cousin Steven had died and we
我表弟史蒂文死了，我们
don't know for sure if Steven went to be
我不确定史蒂文是否会去
with the Lord he did reaffirm to me a
与主一起，他确实向我重申了一个
few months ago that he was trusting in
几个月前，他在信任
Christ but I remember confident
基督， 但我记得自信
insurance
保险
because there wasn't much fruit there in
因为那里没有多少水果
his life but you have a confident hope
他的生活，但你有一个自信的希望
when my dad died and I was away at camp
我父亲去世的时候，我在营地
we came home from camp that afternoon he
那天下午我们从营地回家了
was standing at the end of the counter
站在柜台的尽头
talking to my mom she thought he was
和妈妈说话，她以为他是
teasing her when he fell to the ground
当他倒在地上时戏弄她
but the doctor said he was probably dead
但医生说他可能已经死了
of the heart attack before he hit the
在他击中前的心脏病发作
ground and when Mom met us at the door
当妈妈在门口遇见我们的时候
that afternoon as we came back from the
当天下午我们回来了
Christian camp where we were
基督徒营地我们在哪里
she took Mary Lu in this arm and took me
她带着玛丽鲁的手臂接过我
in the other arm she said we know where
在另一只手臂，她说我们知道在哪里
daddy is and we know we'll see him again
爸爸，我们知道我们会再见到他
she had tears running down her cheeks
她泪流满面地流下了她的脸颊
but she smiled through those tears when
但她笑的时候笑了
she said that we know where daddy is and
她说，我们知道爸爸是和
we know we'll see him again
我们知道我们会再见到他
I know where daddy is I know I will see
我知道爸爸在哪里， 我知道我会看到
him again because I saw the fruit of
他再次因为我看到了果实
Christ in his life and this text says
基督在他的生命和本文中说
listen to it again blessed be the God
再听一遍，祝福是上帝
and father of our Lord Jesus Christ who
和我们的主耶稣基督的父亲是 谁
according to his great mercy not because
根据他的伟大怜悯不是因为
you were such a great guy or a great gal
你是一个伟大的家伙或伟大的加仑
has caused us to be born again to a
已经使我们重生到
Living Hope through the resurrection of
生活希望通过复活
Jesus Christ from the dead to obtain an
从死里复活耶稣基督获得
inheritance which is imperishable and
继承是不可朽坏的
undefiled and will not fade away and
玷污并不会消失，并
will not be taken away by the capital
不会被首都带走
gains tax reserved in heaven for you who
利得税在天上为你保留谁
are protected by the power of God
神的力量保护
through faith for a salvation ready to
通过信仰准备救赎
be revealed in the last time and then
透露，在过去的时间，然后
excite good got one amen all right the
兴奋得好一个阿门好吧
rest of you can will wake up along the
你们其他人都可以沿着这个地方醒来
way oh boy anyway alright so then not
方式哦，男孩反正好，所以不然
only that you have a confident hope of
只有你有自信的希望
eternal life but you are freed from the
永生， 但你从中解脱出来
penalty of sin in Romans chapter 5 and
在罗马书第5章和第5章中对罪的惩罚
and verse 1 you know there is no
和第1节你知道没有
condemnation to those that are in Christ
谴责那些在基督里的人
and there's no fear in death look at
在死亡看来 没有恐惧
what it says in chapter 5 verse 1
它在第5章第1节中所说的内容
therefore having been justified by faith
因此被信仰证明是正当的
we have peace with God through our Lord
我们通过我们的主与上帝和好
Jesus Christ you have peace with God
耶稣基督你与上帝和好
chapter 8 and verse 1 there is there for
第8章和第1节有
now no condemnation for those who are in
现在没有谴责那些谁是
Christ Jesus
基督耶稣
so think about it you know
所以想想你知道
you are justified by faith you have
你有信心，你有正当理由
peace with God as you are justified by
与神和好，你是通过合理
faith and then you also have Christ as
信仰，然后你也有基督作为
your sacrifice he is the one who died in
你的牺牲他就是那个死去的人
your place verse 8 if chapter 5 says you
你的地方第8节，如果第5章说你
know God demonstrated his love toward us
知道上帝展示了他对我们的爱
in that while we were yet sinners Christ
在那时我们还是罪人基督
died for us while you were yet a sinner
当你还是一个罪人时 ，我们为我们而死
while you were living in the sin or
当你生活在罪中或
you're raising your fist in the face of
你面对的是举拳
God and saying Lord I can do it better
上帝，说主我能做得更好
Jesus died for you and then exciting
耶稣为你而死，然后兴奋
that fact alone it gives us hope and so
单凭该事实它给我们带来了希望，因此
you're saved from the wrath of God in
你在上帝的忿怒中得救了
chapter 5 and verse 9 the text tells us
文章告诉我们 ，第 5章和第9节
much more than having now been justified
比现在已经是有道理得多
by his blood we shall be saved from the
用自己的血，我们应从得救
wrath of God through him without Christ
没有基督，借着他的忿怒
the wrath of God abides on you in Christ
上帝的忿怒在基督里住在你身上
you are delivered from that wrath there
你是从那里发怒的
is therefore now no condemnation to
因此现在没有谴责
those who are in Christ Jesus chapter 8
那些在基督耶稣第8章的人
verse one we've already looked at it you
诗一我们已经看了 它，你
will not be condemned you have grace not
不会被谴责你没有恩典
only are you freed from the penalty of
只有你从罚款中解脱出来
sin but you're free from the power of
罪，但你没有权力
sin in Romans chapter 6 and verses 5
在罗马书第6章和第5节中 犯了罪
through 7 you have died with Christ
到了7，你已经与基督同死
therefore you're free from the power of
因此， 你摆脱了它的力量
sin you were dead in your sins but now
罪恶，你现在死在你的罪中
you're alive in Christ and do good works
你在基督里活着并做好事
hey let's go down to the morgue tonight
嘿，让我们今晚去太平间
and let's get a cadaver some of you
让我们一些尸体给你尸体
watch CSI lots of cadavers are you watch
观看CSI 你看的很多尸体
NCIS my wife does not like the parts
NCIS我的妻子不喜欢这些零件
where they're doing that part of the
他们在那里做的那部分
Michelle she likes INSEE is she likes
米歇尔她喜欢INSEE是她喜欢的
the mystery of it try to figure out who
它的奥秘试图找出谁
did it but when the picture comes on and
做到了，但是当图片出现时
they're in the morgue she kind of just
他们在停尸间，她那种只
pulls the you know the blanket up over
拉着你知道毯子了
her head and says they tell me when
她的头说他们什么时候告诉我
they're done with that scene she doesn't
他们完成了她没有的那个场景
like those scenes but you know whether
喜欢那些场景， 但你知道是否
you go down there and you can take a pin
你去那里，你可以采取一个针
and you can poke the cadaver and the
你可以戳尸体和尸体
cadaver won't move
尸体不会动
and now if I come out into the
现在如果我进入了
congregation here this evening
今晚在这里聚会
and I take a pin and I poke you you
我拿一根针给你戳你
probably will move before I get there
在我到达之前可能会移动
with the pin some of you don't even like
用你的一些针甚至不喜欢
being poked with a needle when the
用针刺戳时
doctor is going to give you a shot that
医生打算给你一个机会
you know you need what you see you were
你知道你需要你所看到的
dead in your trespasses and sins and
死在罪恶过 犯 和
only by the grace of God have you been
只有靠着上帝的恩典，你才有过
made alive have you been given the gift
活着，你得到了礼物
of faith and have been then delivered
信仰，然后交付
from the wrath of God and so you were
从上帝的愤怒，所以你是
dead but now you're alive in Christ
死了， 但现在你在基督里活着
that's a tremendous gift from God
这是上帝的巨大礼物
there's a message in this that ought to
这里有一条信息应该是
come through loud and clear and that is
通过大声而清晰的来，就是这样
that when you call the problem of sin
当你称之为罪的问题
you actually are giving hope because
你实际上是在给予希望，因为
Christ died for sinners you see if I'm
基督为罪人而死，你看我是不是
codependent rather than a man pleaser
依赖而不是男人
I'm codependent if I am a sexual addict
如果我是性瘾者，我是相互依赖的
well is there a pill for that can you
那么你可以吃一颗药丸吗？
take something for that if I am an
如果我是一个人，那就拿些东西
alcoholic
酒精
but if that is sin and I call it sin and
但如果这是罪，我称之为罪恶
God sent Christ his own son to die for
上帝差遣基督为自己的儿子而死
that sin then there's hope because we
因为我们，那是罪，那就是希望
can be justified from our sin we can be
可以从我们的罪中得到证明
redeemed from our sin we can be born
从我们的罪中赎回，我们就可以诞生
again a new creation in Christ and
在基督里再创造一个新的创造
that's why the hope is in the Gospel as
这就是福音中的希望
you commit your life to Christ and
你将自己的生命献给基督和
remember the text as it tells us in
记住它告诉我们的文字
first Corinthians 6:9 2:11 it says such
哥林多前书6：9 2:11这样说
were some of you and so the hope is in
是你们中的一些人，所以希望就在这里
Christ in what it says that as Paul
基督就像保罗所说的那样
writes the truth there don't you know
写下真相，你不知道
that the unrighteous will not inherit
不义的人不会继承
the kingdom of God do not be to see
神的国 不要看
neither fornicators nor idolaters nor
既不是奸淫者也不是偶像崇拜者
adulterers nor effeminate nor
奸夫也不是女人
homosexuals nor thieves nor covetous nor
同性恋者也不是小偷，也不是贪婪的
drunkards nor
醉汉也不是
vaulters nor swindlers will inherit the
保镖和诈骗者将继承
kingdom of God such were some of you but
神的国度是这样的你一些，但
you were washed you were sanctified you
你被洗了，你被圣化了
were justified in the name of the Lord
以主的名义称义
Jesus Christ and in the spirit of our
耶稣基督和我们的精神
God
神
you've been justified declared right
你被证明是正确的
before God just as if you never sinned
在上帝面前， 就像你从未犯过罪一样
it is an a declaration it is a decision
这是一个宣言，它是一个决定
that God has made to declare you
上帝已经宣告你了
righteous and such were some of you you
义和这样的都是一些你你
can be a has-been coveter you can be a
可以是一个你可以成为一个很好的人
has-been drunkard you can be a has-been
已经喝醉了你可以成为一个人
adulterer you can meet a has-been
奸夫你可以见面了
swindler you can be a has-been slanderer
骗子你可以成为一个诽谤者
revile er look at me you are looking at
骂你看着我，你在看
saint bomb now I haven't gotten them to
圣炸弹，现在我还没有得到他们对
name a saint Bob's bastards Church yet
说出一个圣徒鲍勃的混蛋教堂
but you see I am a holy one in Christ
但你看我在基督里是圣洁的
you know when you go to Alcoholics
你知道什么时候去酗酒
Anonymous do you really have hope my
匿名，你真的希望我的
name is Bob and I'm an alcoholic
名字叫鲍勃，我是个酗酒者
well my name is Bob and I am a sinner
我的名字是鲍勃，我是一个罪人
who has become a saint and I in Christ I
谁已成为圣徒，我在基督里
am say Bob
我说鲍勃
I am the light of the world I am the
我是世界的光，我的
salt that gives the life flavor I am a
盐给我的生活味道我是一个
son of God I am redeemed I have an
上帝的儿子我得救了我有一个
inheritance that is will not fade away
继承是不会 消失
you can't say that about anything else
你不能说其他任何事情
you don't know whether your real estate
你不知道你的房地产
you know house will still be there for
你知道房子仍然会在那里
your kids to inherit we don't know about
你的孩子继承我们不知道的
those things but what we know about is
那些东西，但我们所知道的是
what we have in Christ and we have real
我们在基督里有什么，我们有真实的
hope we have redemption now the next
希望我们现在能够在下一次赎回
thing is you have so that you can give
你有什么东西可以给你
genuine reasons for real hope you've got
你真正希望的真正原因
all the promises of God in Christ and
在基督里的神的应许，并
again what was said at the beginning
再次在开始时说的话
what Wayne said every counsel he needs
韦恩说他需要的每一个律师
hope you need hope you need hope for
希望你需要希望，你需要希望
today you need hope to get through this
今天你需要希望通过这个
weekend you need some hope tonight who
周末你今晚需要一些希望
the third session starts at 9:40 I know
第三节开始于9:40我知道
because I have to teach that one I know
因为我必须教那个我认识的人
and
和
I gotta drive home then I gotta go up in
我得开车回家然后我得上车
the morning I supposed to be back here
早上我本应该回来
at 8:30 you need some hope
在8:30你需要一些希望
listen promises of God all right you
听神的应许你 没事吧
need hope you got all the promises of
需要希望你得到所有的承诺
God listen to some of them he will work
上帝听 他们会工作的一些人
all things together for good all things
为了好的一切，所有事情都在一起
now in the Greek that actually means all
现在在希腊语中，实际上意味着所有
things it's actually pretty simple
实际上它非常简单
it means the flat tire it means the
它意味着它的瘪胎
cancer it means the death of a loved one
癌症就意味着 爱的人死亡
it means your brother's throwing you
这意味着你的兄弟在扔你
into a pit and selling you into slavery
陷入困境并将你卖给奴隶
it means all things it's very simple
它意味着所有事情都非常简单
Joseph understood that promise we've
约瑟夫明白了我们的承诺
talked about that already he understood
谈到他已经明白了
he said to his brothers who sold him
他对卖掉他的兄弟说
into slavery what you meant for evil God
奴役你对邪恶上帝的意义
meant for good no in the world that
意味着世界上没有好 那
Joseph know that this is Genesis not
约瑟夫知道这不是创世纪
Roman's what books of the Bible did he
罗马是他所做的圣经书籍
have he had a relationship with God he
如果他与上帝有关系他
looked at the Stars and he saw the God
看着星星，他看到了上帝
of creation he knew that God was good
在创造中，他知道上帝是好的
and he knew that God was too wise to
他知道上帝太聪明了
make mistakes and he believed it clear
犯错误，他相信清楚
enough to say what you meant for evil
足以说出你对邪恶的意义
God meant for good he will provide with
上帝意味着他会提供 良好的
your way a victory in every temptation
你的方式在每一个诱惑中取得胜利
or trial think about it 1st Corinthians
或审判考虑哥林多前书
10:13 and 14 very very very very very
10:13和14非常非常非常非常
very very very very very important verse
非常非常非常非常重要的一节
you ought to know it you should have
你应该知道你应该知道的
learned it hopefully with somebody
希望与某人有所学习
disciple in you within a few weeks of
几个星期之内，你的弟子
when you were born again into the
当你重生的时候
kingdom of God there has no temptation
上帝的国度没有诱惑
taken you but such as is common to man
带走了你，但是 对于男人来说是常见的
and God is faithful he will not tempt
上帝是忠诚的，他不会试探
you beyond what you can endure but will
你超出你可以忍受的话，但会
with the temptation make a way of escape
与诱惑作出一种逃避的方式
our God is faithful there are no problem
我们的上帝是忠诚的，没有问题
but such as our
但是比如我们的
common to man Johnny Erickson tada is
男人Johnny Erickson tada是常见的
stretched out in a striker fame after
后来在一名前锋中名声大噪
she has broken her neck a striker frame
她的脖子上有一个前锋框架
is simply a round circular frame with
简直就是一个圆形的圆形框架
the canvas inside and what they do is
里面的画布和他们做的是
put you inside the canvas like a
把你放在画布里面就像一个
sandwich and it holds you perfectly
三明治，它完美地拥抱着你
still but they can turn you so they can
仍然但是他们可以把你这样他们就可以
turn you upside down or a right side up
把你颠倒过来或右上角
on they can turn you always so the you
他们可以永远把你变成你
know keep circulation going that way but
知道保持流通的方式，但是
you don't have to move you you're not on
你没有动你，你不能在
a bed so they don't have to move you to
一张床，所以他们不必搬你
do this and there's a fly buzzing around
做到这一点，有一只苍蝇嗡嗡左右
their face and it's crawling on her lips
他们的脸，它在她的嘴唇上爬行
and crawling on her nose and she's
并且爬在她的鼻子上， 她是
trying to get that thing off and and
试图让事情关闭，并
trying to get her but she can't brush it
想要得到她，但她无法刷它
away because she has no movement she's a
离开， 因为她没有运动，她是一个
quadriplegic now and she cries out to
现在四肢瘫痪，她大声呼喊
God and says god you don't know what
上帝，说上帝，你不知道是什么
it's like and then she thought wait
它就像，然后她想等
Christ was on the cross it's the Middle
基督在十字架上是中间的
East he was bloody had to be flies
东方他血腥不得不过得很快
crawling on his wounds that he couldn't
在他的伤口上爬行他不能
get off he does know see there's no
下车，他知道看到没有
temptation but such as is common to man
诱惑，但这是人类共同的
and God is faithful he'd ever ever give
上帝是他永远奉献的忠诚
you more than you can endure he's like a
你不仅可以忍受他就像一个人
good coach he will push you a lot
好教练他会推动你很多
further than you think you can go but he
比你认为你可以去，但他
will never give you more than you can
永远不会给你超过你
endure so whatever you're facing right
无论你面对什么，都要忍受
now you need to think wait a minute
现在你需要想 等一下
I don't think I can handle this but God
我不认为我可以处理这个，但上帝
thinks I can handle it and therefore he
认为我可以处理它，因此他
has given it to me for the purpose of my
为了我的目的，我已经把它给了我
growth and he will provide the way of
增长和他将提供的方式
escape that's there
逃脱的存在
so in this text the word temptation can
因此在本文中，诱惑这个词可以
be tempted temptation or trial you check
被诱惑诱惑或审判你检查
it out it's a test of your faith and you
它是对你和你的信仰的考验
don't want see if it's just a trial flat
不想看它是否只是平试用
tire that immediately goes to temptation
轮胎， 立即诱惑
to do what crumbling come
做什么摇摇欲坠的来
of course what do you do oh my goodness
当然，你做了什么哦，我的天啊
I got a flat tire huh I got too many
轮胎漏气了我有太多了
things to do today I can't take time to
今天要做的事我不能抽时间
change a flat tire on world what am I
改变世界上一个瘪胎是什么我
gonna do what are we doing sinning
要做我们犯罪的事情
we're grumbling we're complaining and I
我们抱怨我们抱怨和我
think there's that verse in Philippians
我认为腓立比书中有那节经文
someplace do all things without
某个地方做所有事情都没有
grumbling and complaining not some
抱怨和抱怨不是一些
things not many things not most things
事情并不多， 不是大多数事情
but all things and what do we do well we
但是所有事情以及我们做得怎么样
grumble and complain about almost
几乎抱怨和抱怨
everything we just kind of flipped that
我们只是简单地翻了一下
verse on its head and do all things
在它的头上， 做所有的事情
without coming in complaining oh do
没有抱怨哦
everything with grumbling and
抱怨和抱怨的一切
complaining and and we're sinning and
抱怨和我们犯罪了
what are we doing when we sin like that
当我们这样犯罪时 ，我们在做什么
shaking my fist in the face of my
摇我的拳头在面对 我的
Almighty God and saying god I know it's
全能的上帝，说上帝，我知道它
best today and what was best was not a
今天最好，最好的不是
flat tire thank you very much and I'm
爆胎非常感谢你，我
not interested in changing that flat
改变那个单位不感兴趣
tire it's gonna mess up my whole day
轮胎它会让我整天都搞砸了
when God has said I will work all things
当上帝说我会做所有的事情
together for good
一起好
including the flat tire that you can't
包括你不能 的瘪胎
afford in your schedule what God is
在你的日程表中承担上帝的本性
doing is blueprinting over your schedule
做的是蓝图，超过你的日程安排
and he's got something else in mind
而且他还有别的想法
for us to work on and so within that
让我们继续努力
you've got hope it cuz your problems are
你有希望，因为你的问题是
common and you have hope because God is
共同的，你有希望因为上帝
faithful and you have hope because God
忠心，你有希望，因为上帝
provides the way of escape so that you
为你提供逃生的方式
can endure it and the next verse says
可以忍受它，下一节经文说
then flee from idolatry so that's part
然后逃离偶像崇拜，这是其中的一部分
of it as you resist temptation and as
当你抵抗诱惑和那样的时候
you commit yourself to the faithfulness
你忠诚于忠诚
of God flee from those things that would
上帝逃避那些会发生的事情
cause idolatry he will never leave us or
因为偶像崇拜， 他永远不会离开我们或
forsake us Hebrews 13:5 you have a
离弃我们希伯来书13：5 你有一个
promise that God will never leave you or
保证上帝永远不会离开你或
forsake what did Jesus say on the cross
放弃了耶稣在十字架上说的话
he said my God my God why has thou
他说我的上帝我的上帝你为什么
forsaken me he was forsaken
离弃我， 他被遗弃了
so that you might never have to be
所以你可能永远不必
forsaken he was all alone bearing your
被遗弃他独自一人承担你的责任
sin but you will never be alone
罪，但你永远不会孤单
you will feel alone I felt alone
你会感到孤单，我感到孤独
when I went through depression I felt
当我经历抑郁时，我感觉到了
like God had deserted me but he hadn't
就像上帝抛弃了我，但他没有
and he doesn't but the fact is he's
他没有，但事实是他的
there and he will never learn he will
在那里，他永远不会知道他会
always be our helper in Hebrews 13 6 he
在希伯来书13 6他总是我们的帮助者
is your helper and you need him every
是你的帮助者，你需要他
moment the problem is we forget to ask
那一刻问题是我们忘了问
you know we've been looking for the keys
你知道我们一直在寻找钥匙
for 30 minutes and finally we stop and
30分钟， 最后我们停下来
say lord I don't know where the keys are
说主我不知道钥匙在哪里
you know where the keys are
你知道钥匙的位置
would you please reveal to me where I
请你告诉我我在哪里
left the keys I know I should remember
离开我知道我应该记住的钥匙
myself but I don't we forget to ask when
我自己， 但我不忘记什么时候问
it says in everything we are to pray
它说我们要祈祷的一切
pray without ceasing he'll forgive our
不停地祈祷他会原谅我们的
sins first John 1:9 if we confess our
如果我们承认我们的话，约翰福音1：9 就会犯罪
sins he's faithful and just to forgive
他是忠诚的，只是为了原谅
us our sins and cleanse us from all
我们的罪孽和清洁我们所有人
unrighteousness what do you have to do I
不义你有什么我要做的
got to do some penance I got to make up
要做一些忏悔我来弥补
for this no you have to confess it
为此，你不得不承认它
what does confess it mean homologue a it
什么承认它意味着同源它
means call it what it is Lord that was
意思是称之为主是什么
rude
无礼
so that was impatience or that was lack
所以这是不耐烦或缺乏
of self-control Lord that was lack of
缺乏自我控制的主
love Lord that was unkind or that wasn't
爱不友善的主或者不爱的主
gentle just call it sin and what happens
温柔地称之为罪，发生了什么
he cleanses you you I thank God for hot
他给你洗净你我感谢上帝的热情
showers do you ever think God for hot
淋浴你有没有想过上帝的热情
showers it's a wonderful privilege you
淋浴这是一个美妙的特权你
know when I couldn't take a shower when
知道什么时候我不能洗澡
I had my back surgery it was miserable
我做了背部手术，很痛苦
but taking a hot showers of probably you
但可能是你的热水淋浴
need up every time you sinned need a hot
每次你犯罪时都需要热火
shower just call it Lord that was sin
淋浴只是称它为罪，这是罪
that was unkind but that was rude
那是不友好的， 但那很粗鲁
and when you do he cleanses you from
当你这样做时，他会给你洗净
that sin and from all unrighteousness
那罪和所有不义
because you know you don't keep up you
因为你知道你跟不上你
sin so often you can't keep up I'm not
所以经常你不能跟上罪我不是
picking on you I often I can't keep up
挑选你我常常跟不上
either okay but that's the truth think
无论是好的，但这是事实觉得
about it how many times do you think
关于它你有多少次想到
you've complained today without ever
你今天没有抱怨过
recognizing that it was grumbling and
意识到这是抱怨和
complaining and without ever can
抱怨，没有
passing it is sin how many times do you
传递是罪有多少次你
think you might have been unkind or lack
认为你可能是不友善或缺乏
gentleness or lacked self-control
温柔或缺乏自制力
but you never consciously stopped and
但你从来没有有意识地停下来
said Lord that was sin how many times
主说这是罪多少次
you think so when you do realize and you
当你意识到和你在一起 时，你是这么想的
do confess this verse says if we confess
如果我们承认，请承认这节经文
our saying he's faithful and just to
我们说他忠实而公正
forgive us our sins and cleanse us from
原谅我们的罪过并清除我们的罪孽
all unrighteousness
所有的不义
he catches us up God covers it all
他抓住我们上帝掩盖了一切
and then he'll call our sins to head his
然后他会称我们的罪过他的罪
mind against us no more see I am under
我们心里不再看见我了
the blood so when Jesus when God sees to
当耶稣在上帝看见时，血就如此
me he sees me through the blood of
我， 他通过血液看到我
Christ
基督
as justified as one who has made holy as
像圣洁的人一样合理
Saint Bob now think about it the church
圣鲍勃现在想起教堂
at Corinth had what more problems than
在科林斯有更多的问题而不是
any other church right how's it started
任何其他教会的权利最近怎么 开始
- the saint set Corinth Saints who were
-圣设定科林斯圣徒是谁
letting people get away with incest in
让人们逃避乱伦
the church pretty shaky man they really
教会他们真的很不稳定
saved - the Saints at Corinth and we are
救了- 在哥林多的圣徒和我们
Saints in Christ and that means he
在基督里的圣徒，这意味着他
doesn't call to mind our sins against us
不要忘记我们对我们的罪过
he'll guide us proverbs 3:5 and 6
他会引导我们箴言3：5和6
you know don't lean on your own
你知道不靠自己
understanding but in all your ways
理解，但在你的方式
acknowledge him and he will direct your
承认他，他将指导你
path oh that's cool you don't have to
路径哦，你没必要 这很酷
know what you're gonna do next year or
知道你明年或将要做什么
five years from now you just need to I
五年后你才需要我
need to acknowledge the Lord today Lord
需要承认上帝耶和华的今天
what do you want me to do today well and
你今天要我做什么呢？
everything give thanks for that's the
一切都要感谢你的
will of God for you in Christ Jesus okay
在基督耶稣里，上帝的旨意好吧
gonna give thanks for everything that
要感谢所有的一切
happens today I know that's right I can
今天发生， 我知道我能做到
do it I don't know what just do the next
这样做我不知道下一步该做什么
right thing what's coming up next well
正确的事情接下来会发生什么
do my best to pay attention in spite of
尽管如此，尽我所能去关注
the fact that I'm exhausted I don't know
事实上，我很累，我不知道
if I'm gonna keep awake and I'm fighting
如果我要保持清醒而且我正在战斗
it but I'm gonna do my best to pay
它，但我会尽我所能支付
attention and so do that next best thing
注意， 以及下一个最好的事情
he'll complete is working as Flip Ian's
他将完成作为Flip Ian的工作
1:6 I love it there are no unfinished
1：6我爱它没有未完成的
projects in God's garage there are some
在上帝的车库里有一些项目
in yours there are some in mind you know
在你的脑海里有一些你知道的
I've been in my house for a year and a
我已经在我家里呆了一年了
half now
现在一半
with the intent of cleaning out the
旨在清理掉
garage it's still not cleaned out I
车库它还没有清理掉我
might look nicer than yours I don't know
可能看起来比你的更好，我不知道
I don't know what yours looks like but
我不知道你的样子但是
it doesn't look up to snuff and in your
它不会嗅到鼻烟和你的鼻烟
closet you know for I think it's three
你知道的壁橱，我认为这是三个
years now we've been planning to take
多年来我们一直在计划采取
all of our old albums and turn them into
我们所有的老专辑都把它们变成了
you know CDs and you know give that as a
你知道CD，你知道这是一个
gift to the kids for Christmas well this
礼物给孩子们圣诞节这个
isn't it's not gonna get done this
是不是它拿不到这样做
Christmas either but Philippians 1:6
圣诞节要么是腓立比书1：6
says God has begun a good work in you
说上帝已经在你身上开始了一项好工作
and he will complete it and this
他将完成它和这个
remember this too that means you're a
记住这也意味着你是一个
work in process you are not perfect yet
在工作过程中你是不是很完美
so but you are forgiven that's wonderful
所以，你被宽恕了
he will hear our prayers John 16 24 and
他会听到我们的祈祷约翰福音16 24和24
Psalm 34 15 you know he God listens to
诗篇34 15你知道他是上帝所听的
your prayers
你的祈祷
you know what the psalmist said in Psalm
你知道诗篇作者在诗篇中所说的话
116 I think it's first one the psalmist
116我认为这是第一个诗篇作者
said I love the Lord God because he
说我爱主神，因为他
listens to my prayers that's why you got
倾听我的祈祷，这就是你得到的原因
to listen to people who you're
倾听你的人
counseling demonstrate to them your
咨询向他们证明你的
involvement your love for them by
通过参与你对他们的爱
listening to them until you understand
听你的话，直到你明白
what the issues are that they're dealing
他们正在处理的问题是什么
with but though God listens to you I
虽然上帝听你的，但我
wake up every night in the night two
每天晚上醒来夜里两点
three times
三次
God hears my prayers my wife's asleep I
上帝听到我的妻子睡着了我的祈祷
don't want to book her but I can talk to
不想预定她，但我可以和她说话
God and he hears our prayers
上帝和他听到了我们的祈祷
he'll just discipline us proverbs 3:11
他只会训练我们箴言3:11
Hebrews 12:5 to eat he will discipline
希伯来书12：5 吃饭，他会管教
on he's a loving Heavenly Father you
对他是一个慈爱的天父你
don't want your kids to stick Forks in
不想让你的孩子必须在福克斯
light sockets you don't want your kids
你不想要你的孩子的灯座
to rob the traffic I pulled into a
抢劫我拉进的交通
parking lot at Panera Bread where my
停车场在Panera Bread的地方我
wife and I had a substitute for supper
妻子和我有一个替代晚餐
tonight and pulled into the parking lot
今晚拉进了停车场
it you know the kid started to go out
你知道孩子出门了
this way in into the and on the lane in
这种方式进入和在车道上
the parking lot dad reached out grabbed
停车场爸爸伸出手抓住了
up a tune he came back you know just
他回来后你就知道了
that quick I mean the kid went three
那么快我的意思是这个孩子三岁了
steps I just happened to be looking in
步骤我只是碰巧在看
that direction because I saw the people
那个方向，因为我看到了人民
getting out of that car and I'm coming
走出那辆车，我来了
in and I looked there and the kid just
在我看着那里，孩子刚
takes about three
需要大约三个
step started to run and then beheads him
一步开始跑，然后斩首他
and brought him back it's a loving
并把他带回来这是一个爱
father I want you just let the kid run
父亲我想要你让孩子跑
free because he saw me coming
免费，因为他看到我来了
and so the loving Heavenly Father
所以爱天父
disciplines us so that we might grow he
训练我们，以便我们可以成长他
will strengthen us Philippians 4:13 I
会加强我们腓立比书4:13我
can do all things through Christ who
可以通过基督来做所有事情
strengthens me not some things not most
不是最重要的事情，不是强化我
things I'm anything anything he calls me
事我什么都不称呼我
to do I can do in him you could survive
我可以做到他能活下去
till tomorrow afternoon
直到明天下午
trust me okay he will not withhold any
相信我，他不会扣留任何东西
good thing from us oh that's neat so if
我们的好东西哦，如果那么整洁
he withheld it must be it wasn't a good
他保留了它一定不是好事
thing my wife has a bonus prayer list
我想我的妻子有一个奖金祈祷名单
and they praised something like this
他们称赞这样的事情
Lord if it would be good for me and it
主啊，如果它对我和它有好处
would bring glory to you and it would
会给你带来荣耀，它会
delight your heart to delight my heart I
满足您的心脏取悦我的心脏我
would like this but you see she couches
我想要这样，但你看到她的沙发
what she's asking for in that bonus
她在奖金中要求的是什么
prayer list because it's not a need list
祷告清单，因为它不是需要清单
it's a bonus prayer list
这是一个额外的祈祷名单
she couches it with if it would be good
如果它会好的话，她会用它来安抚它
for me and it would bring glory to you
对我而言，它会给你带来荣耀
then it would delight my heart if you
那么如果你愿意，我会很高兴
would but if it's not good for me and it
但如果这对我和它 都不好
won't bring glory for you or don't do it
不会为你带来荣耀或不做
so he wanted withhold any good thing he
所以他想要保留任何好事
will keep us from harm that's a
会让我们免受伤害
marvelous promise as well the Lord Jesus
主耶稣也是一个奇妙的应许
Christ will keep us from all harm and
基督将使我们免受一切伤害
working in us in those ways and then not
以这种方式在我们身边工作然后没有
only that but he will provide what we
只有这样，但他会提供我们的
need Philippians 4:19 couched in the
需要腓4:19埋伏在
context there as the Philippians are
像腓立比人那样
giving to God and providing for Paul the
赐给上帝并赐予保罗
missionary God says to them through Paul
传教士上帝通过保罗对他们说
you know out of his riches in glory not
你知道他的荣耀中没有 财富
out if his miser leanness out of his
如果他的吝啬鬼脱离他的
riches he will provide all that we need
他将提供我们所需要的所有财富
he can do that in magnificent and
他可以做到这一点
glorious ways he can provide everything
他能提供一切的光荣方式
that we need and so we need to trust him
我们需要，所以我们需要相信他
to do that he uses trials to strengthen
为此，他使用试验加强
us James 1:2 to 4
我们詹姆斯1：2到4
my brethren count it all joy when you
我的弟兄们，你们这一切都是快乐的
fall into various trials knowing that
知道这一点落入各种试验
the trying or the testing of your faith
尝试或测试你的信仰
produces perseverance and endurance God
产生坚持不懈和耐力的上帝
has given you that trial to bring about
已经给你试验带来了
growth in your life and so he provides
在你的生活中成长，所以他提供
that trial to strengthen you to cause
那次审判加强了你的事业
you to grow in every way then again he's
你会以各种方式成长，然后又是他
gonna welcome us into glory
要欢迎我们进入荣耀
you know first uh slowly ins in chapter
你知道的第一个呃慢慢地插入章节
4 verses 15 to 18 the dead in Christ
在基督里死了4节15到18节
will rise first and as Christ is coming
当基督降临时，他会先起来
down we'll be caught up together with
下来，我们会赶上 一起
them and we will meet the Lord in the
他们，我们将满足主在
clouds we get to go to be with Jesus we
云我们要和耶稣在一起
are looking forward to the Blessed hope
期待盼望的福
we're looking forward to the return of
我们期待着回归
Christ we are looking forward to the
基督，我们期待着
millennial reign of Christ we are I have
基督的千年统治我们是我
a hope that brings us into that look can
把我们带入那种外表的希望可以
you imagine it you will reign with
你想象一下，你将统治它
Christ you get to be mayor of a city as
基督， 你将成为一个城市的市长
you're faithful to him however that
然而， 你对他很忠诚
works out some of you will be over more
找出你们中的一些人会更多
than one city you will be working out
你会在 一个城市 工作
the details all the things that are
细节所有的事情
being messed up today because of sin you
被搞砸了，因为今天罪恶，你会
and your glorified body with your
和你的荣耀的身体
glorified mind will be able to take the
荣耀的心灵将能够占有
Word of God and apply it and what if we
上帝的话并应用它，如果我们如何
just kept one commandment in America
只是在美国保留了一条诫命
let's just say we kept the commandment
我们只是说我们遵守诫命
thou shalt not steal
你不会偷
would it be nice to live here you don't
住在这里你会不会很高兴
have to lock the cars you don't have to
必须锁定你不需要的汽车
have a safe in the house they don't have
有一个安全的房子，他们没有
to have security at the store I read one
我在商店看到一个安全保障
article that said every article would
文章说每篇文章都会
drop at least 20% in cost immediately if
如果，立即降低至少20％的成本
there was no security that required to
没有必要的安全措施
protect that item all along the way
在整个过程中保护该项目
nobody would do to anything you know
没有人会对你知道的任何事情做过
anyone anything to anyone that wasn't
任何人任何事任何人，这不是
what they would like to have done to
他们想什么都做了
them thou shalt not steal we just kept
他们你不能偷我们只是保持
that one this would be great what if we
如果我们这样的话会很棒
kept the 1000 I commit adultery
保持1000我通奸
everybody was faithful to their wife or
每个人都忠实于他们的妻子或
to their husband for life whoa nice
对他们的丈夫来说，生活中的美好
place to live
住的地方
so you know he's gonna welcome us into
所以你知道他会欢迎我们进入
glory and we're gonna have a chance to
荣耀，我们将有机会
reign with him you've got a high priest
和他一起统治你有一位大祭司
who's there to help you in every need
谁在那里帮助你满足每一个需求
Hebrews 4 15 and 16 it's a text that you
希伯来书415和16这是你的文字
want to go back to and back to and back
我想回去和回去
to over and over again as you as you
和你一样一遍又一遍
give hope to individuals in their trials
给试验中的个人带来希望
it tells us there that Jesus Christ is
它告诉我们有耶稣基督是
our high priest and as our high priest
我们的大祭司和我们的大祭司
he's been tempted in all points as we
就像我们一样，他在所有方面都受到诱惑
have been and yet he is without sin and
已经然而他没有罪和
did not demonstrate weakness so
并没有表现出如此的弱点
therefore let us draw near with
因此，让我们与亲近
confidence to the throne of grace so
信心的恩典的宝座等等
that we may receive mercy and find grace
我们可以得到怜悯并找到恩典
to help in time of need you know I just
在需要的时候帮助你，我知道
want justice know you know I know you
想要正义知道你知道我认识你
know what I would get if I got what I
知道如果我得到了什么，我会得到什么
deserved you know what I would get hell
当之无愧你知道我会得到地狱
forever I don't want that I want justice
永远我不希望我想要正义
I want mercy and I want grace and where
我想要怜悯，我想要恩典和地方
when we come to the throne we come to a
当我们来到王位时， 我们来到了
throne of grace where we get mercy and
我们得到怜悯的恩典宝座
grace in that marvelous when we pray
当我们祈祷时，在那奇妙的恩典中
tonight before we started we came to a
今晚 我们开始之前，我们来到了一个
throne of grace and we received grace
恩典的宝座， 我们得到了恩典
and we received mercy in our knee and
我们膝盖和怜悯
that's the wonderful glory that we have
这是我们拥有的美妙荣耀
in Christ and he has faced every
在基督里，他面对每一个人
temptation and he was victorious and
诱惑，他胜利了
then we draw near because he understands
然后我们靠近， 因为他理解
us because he's been through it remember
我们，因为他经历过它
the illustration from Johnnie Erickson
约翰尼埃里克森的插图
tada you can't name ah never been
田田你不能名字啊从来没有
rejected like I was oh wait a minute
像我一样被拒绝哦等一下
how about having Peter one of your three
如何让彼得成为你的三个人之一
intimate disciples curse and say he
亲密的弟子诅咒并说出他
never knew you on the night your being
从来没有认识过你
betrayed that's kind of being rejected
背叛了那种被拒绝的人
isn't it and he came to his own people
不是吗，他来到了自己的人民
the Jews whom he had prepared for
他 为 他准备的犹太人
thousands of years they did not receive
几千年来他们没有收到
him they crucified Him and he
他将他和他 钉在十字架上
understands and then you draw near in
理解，然后你在附近画画
confidence because he never yielded and
信心，因为他从来没有屈服过
it's a throne of grace and he gives
这是一个恩典的宝座，他给了
mercy and grace
怜悯和恩典
in time of need and then not only that
在需要的时候，不仅如此
but your high priest has the authority
但你的大祭司有权威
and the power to help and Jesus teaches
以及帮助和耶稣教导的力量
in mark 1:22 with authority it says and
在标记1:22中有权威它说和
the people were amazed because he taught
因为他教导人们感到惊讶
with authority he didn't say this rabbi
有权威的他没有说这个拉比
says this and this rabbi says this and
说这个， 这个拉比说这个和
you can take your pick
你可以选择
jesus said you have heard it said but I
耶稣说你听说过但我说
say unto you he taught with authority
对他说，他教授权威
and when you get into a counseling room
当你进入咨询室
you can teach with authority if you hold
如果你持有，你可以授权
your finger on the text and you say this
你的手指在文字上，你说这个
is what God says I know as the man said
正如那人说的那样， 是上帝所说的
in my office this week well I had a
本周在我的办公室里，我有一个
dream last night in my dream it was so
昨晚在我的梦中做梦就是这样
dark and I was a guy that came out of
黑暗，我是一个出来的人
the corner of the room and he said Jesus
在房间的角落，他说耶稣
has rejected you and I said but I can
拒绝了你，我说但是我可以
hold my finger on this text and it says
我把手指放在这个文本上然后说
Jesus will never leave you or forsake
耶稣永远不会离开你或离弃
you and you know what caused that dream
你和你知道是什么导致了这个梦想
what you need to say is when you wake up
你需要说的就是你醒来的时候
thank God that was a dream because
感谢上帝，这是一个梦想， 因为
dreams can't hurt you oh you say you
梦想不能伤害你哦你说你
haven't had dream like my dreams hey
没有梦想像我的梦想嘿
it's a dream a dream is a dream this is
这是一个梦想梦想是梦想，这是
God's Word it has lasted forever and you
上帝的话语 永远持续着你
know the amazing truth of this word is
知道这个词的惊人真相
you know Nietzsche said God is dead but
你知道尼采说上帝死了但是
now Nietzsche is dead and it's signed
现在尼采已经死了，而且签了名
God because he said every man will die
上帝， 因为他说每个人都会死
and I'm trying to think of the man now
我试图现在想起来的男人
and his name escapes me right now who
而他的名字现在逃脱了我
who printed the atheistic tracts and
谁打印了无神论的小册子和
then when he died the Geneva Bible
那时他死于日内瓦圣经
Society bought his press and started
社会买了他的新闻并开始了
printing Bibles on it and I'm his it'll
打印圣经，我就是他的
come to me about two o'clock in the
大约两点钟来找我
morning I'll remember it I'll tell you
早上我会记住它我会告诉你的
tomorrow okay but that's the idea is God
明天没事，但那就是上帝的想法
is eternal he's never yielded his throne
是永恒的，他永远不会屈服于他的宝座
is a throne of grace he gives you mercy
是恩惠的宝座，他赐给你怜悯
and grace and he has then power think
和恩典，他有权力思考
about it he sends his disciples out to
关于它，他派他的门徒出去
minister on the basis of his power what
部长在他的权力的基础上什么
does he say to them all authority has
他是否对所有权威人士说过
been given to me and I send you go make
被送给我，我发给你去做
disciples baptizing them and teaching
门徒给他们施洗和教学
them to observe all the things that I
他们要观察我所有的事情
have taught you
教过你
and then just look at this list Jesus
然后只看这个列表耶稣
has authority over what in the book of
对书中的内容有权威
mark unclean spirits fever disease
标志着不洁的精神发烧病
demons leprosy paralysis men Levi's the
恶魔麻风瘫痪男人李维斯
tax collector the deformity remember the
税收者畸形记住了
guy Jesus gets upset with the people
耶稣对人民感到不安
that are there there's a man there with
是有有一个男人那里
a deformed hand and they're just waiting
一只变形的手，他们只是在等待
to see what Jesus will do cuz it's a
看耶稣会做什么，因为它是一个
Sabbath day is he gonna break the
安息日是他要打破的
Sabbath day in their minds break the
他们心中的安息日打破了
Sabbath day because they've got these
安息日， 因为他们有这些
rules but they've added to what God says
规则， 但他们增加了上帝所说的
about the Sabbath day is he gonna heal
关于安息日是，他该怎么医治
this guy I would have liked to have been
这个家伙我本来 一直
there and seen it and this Jesus says
在那里，看到它和耶稣说
speaks to him in his hand just becomes
他手里的他说话就变成了
whole and one of those guys do they
整个和其中一个人做他们
start to plot to kill him but Jesus has
开始策划杀死他，但耶稣有
the power he has a power over Levi the
他对列维拥有权力的权力
tax collector no that's something you
税吏没有你的意思
know the tax collector you know comes
知道你知道税吏 来
and follows him then he has authority
并跟着他， 然后他有权威
over many demons and over long term
超过许多恶魔和长期
illness and over death and over hunger
疾病，过度死亡和过度饥饿
and he can feed five thousand over the
他可以养活5000 在
elements over water he can walk on it
水上的元素，他可以走在它上面
over the wind and the waves he can
他可以在风和海浪上
control them I don't like to bend there
控制他们， 我不喜欢那里弯曲
then to you know all of a sudden just
然后你知道一下子刚
become perfectly quiet and the wind has
变得非常安静，风也有
been roaring and the waves have been up
咆哮着，海浪一直在上升
there and all said perfect calm and the
那里和所有人说完美的平静和
disciples are afraid in the presence of
门徒们害怕在场
that power but he has authority over the
该权力，但他有权 在
traditions of men he has authority over
男人的传统他有权威
birth defects he has authority over
出生缺陷他有权威
blindness he has authority over the
失明，他拥有的权力
grave I would have liked to have been
坟墓我本来希望过
there to when they approached the the
在那里，当他们走近了
casket you know the guys that are
棺材， 你知道那些人
carrying the stretcher would the widow
寡妇带着担架
of nain son you know what would you have
你知道你会有什么儿子
done if you had been one of the guys
如果你是其中一个人就完成了
carrying the stretcher when Jesus spoke
耶稣说话时带着担架
to the guy and the guy sat out you to
的家伙的家伙坐在了 你
drop the stretcher the guy would have
放下那个家伙会担架的担架
broken his neck and Jesus would have had
打破了他的脖子，耶稣会有
to heal him again but that's what I
再次治愈他，但这就是我
would have been done uh how would is it
本来会怎么做的呃它会怎么样
whoa I'm out of here what a picture of
哇， 我离开这里的照片是什么
the power of Christ but not only that
基督的能力， 但不仅如此
you have another reason for hope God's
你有另一个 希望上帝的理由
peace and joy are always available to
平安和喜乐始终可用
you and are not dependent on your
你并不依赖于你
circumstances the Word of God gives
上帝的话给出的情况
peace but it's not like the peace that
和平，但它不像和平那样
that we can give and well as we speak
在我们发言时我们可以给予和好
peace but rather in the peace of God we
和平，而不是在上帝的平安中，我们
have complete peace and complete joy and
有完全的平安和完全的快乐
complete strength in him and so the
他完全有力量等等
thinking here look at what it says in
想到这里看看它说的是什么
your text in John 14:27 that Jesus says
您在约翰福音14:27文本 ，耶稣说：
I give peace but it's not like the
我给予和平，但它不像
world's peace I give peace to you that
世界和平我给你和平
peace is the peace my mom had we know
和平是我妈妈所知道的和平
where daddy is and we know we'll see him
爸爸在哪儿，我们知道我们会见到他
again
再次
my mom was 50 or 51 when my dad died my
我的妈妈是50或51的时候我爸爸死了我
mom lived to be a hundred
妈妈活到百岁
dad mom were married they had 27 years
爸爸妈妈结婚了他们有27年了
of marriage together their mom lived
婚姻的 他们一起生活的妈妈
another 50 years just trusting in Jesus
再过50年，只相信耶稣
but in going home to Jesus still had
但回家的时候耶稣仍然有
that confident faith she was going home
她有信心回家了
to Jesus and she was going to see Dad
对耶稣而言，她会去见爸爸
again and all the others that had gone
再次和所有其他已经消失的人
on before we have peace that passes
在我们通过和平之前
understanding that's what it talks about
理解这就是它所谈论的内容
in Philippians 4 6 and 7 be anxious for
腓立比书4 6和7急于求成
nothing that's a command be don't let's
没有什么是命令是不要让我们
go back to the sin thing if we confess
如果我们承认，回到罪恶的事情
our sin he's faithful and just to
我们的罪是他的忠诚和公正
forgive us and cleanse us from all
原谅我们，并 从所有 洗净我们
unrighteousness you know how many things
不义你知道有多少事
have you worried about this week without
你有没有担心这个星期没有
calling it sinned and without confessing
称它犯了罪，没有承认
it be anxious for nothing do not worry
它无所畏惧，不用担心
about anything
什么都有
the traffic is heavy coming over the
交通堵塞了
hill tonight will I get there on time
我今晚将按时赶到那里
don't worry about anything that's the
不用担心任何事情是这样的
one that comes to my mind right now I
我现在想到的一个
did not confess that worry to God and I
没有向上帝和我承认这种担心
didn't confess the grumbling I did about
没有承认我所做的抱怨
it to God so I'll take care of that
它归于上帝所以我会照顾它
later right now I got to keep talking to
后来，现在我一定要坚持交谈
you all right but you know it's sin be
你没事，但你知道这是罪
anxious for nothing but in everything by
除了一切之外什么都不要紧张
prayer general prayer and supplication
祷告一般祷告和恳求
specific petition let your requests be
具体请愿请求
made known to God with Thanksgiving
感恩节让上帝知道
thank you
谢谢
for this problem why thank him because
对于这个问题为什么要感谢他，因为
all things work together for good and
所有的事情都是一起努力的
then you know you commit that to him in
然后你知道你把它交给了他
prayer and you trust in him and you give
祈祷，你相信他，你给予
that to him and he gives you grace and
对他而言，他给了你恩典和
strength and peace that goes beyond
超越的力量与和平
understanding the way to have joy in
认识到有欢乐的方式
pieces to abide in his Commandments John
要遵守他的诫命约翰
15 10 11 you want to walk in his
15 10 11你想要走进他的
Commandments trust and obey for there's
诫命信任并服从于此
no other way you know to have the
没有其他你知道的方式
strength and the peace that we can have
实力， 我们可以有和平
in Christ Christ has overcome the world
在基督里， 基督已经战胜了世界
and therefore you have P think about
因此你有P思考
Paul and Silas they got their feet in
保罗和西拉斯他们站了起来
stocks and their hands in stock their
股票和他们的股票他们的股票
backs are bloody from the meeting that
从那次会议来看，后面是血腥的
they've had and what are they doing
他们已经拥有了，他们在做什么
grumbling and complaining no I think the
抱怨和抱怨没有我认为
text says they were singing praises in
文字说他们在唱歌赞美
the middle of the battle I will praise
在战斗的中间我会赞美
him in the middle of it all of us his
他在 我们所有人的中间他
name I don't know if that's the one they
名字我不知道他们是不是那个人
were singing but they were singing so
他们正在唱歌，但他们正在唱歌
God shook the earth a little bit threw
上帝有点扔了一下震动了地球
open all the doors set them free from
打开所有的门让他们摆脱
the stalks Philippian jailer thinks oh
秸秆腓立比狱卒认为哦
I'm gonna catch it now my prisoners have
我现在要抓住它了我的囚犯
all gotten loose he's ready to do
一切都松了，他已经准备好了
himself in got the sword ready to kill
他自己准备好杀死剑
himself because he's just gonna save the
他自己， 因为他只是要拯救
authorities time because if he loses his
当局因为如果他输了他的话
prisoners that's what they do to him
囚犯就是他们对他的所作所为
Paul says you know he says when he finds
保罗说，你知道，当他发现，他说：
out Paul's there don't worry we're all
保罗在那里不用担心我们都是
here and he said what must I do to be
在这里，他说我必须做些什么
saved and he says you know believe on
救了，他说你知道相信
the Lord Jesus Christ and thou shalt be
主耶稣基督，你将成为
saved
保存
talking to suicidal people keep it brief
与自杀的人交谈时要保持简短
and you know you and your house and that
你知道你和你的房子和
night they have a baptismal service you
晚上他们有洗礼服务你
know and because Christ can overcome and
知道， 因为基督可以克服和
he can give you peace you have love and
他可以给你平安， 你有爱和
joy and peace they're the fruit of the
喜悦与和平是他们的成果
Spirit you don't think about the fruit
精神你不要考虑水果
of the Spirit
精神
Bob joy peace love joy peace those are
鲍勃喜悦和平爱这喜欢和平
the first three that are listed as the
被列为 前三
fruit of the Spirit as he's producing
他正在生产圣灵的果子
that in your life there's another thing
在你的生活中还有另外一件事
that gives you confident hope as a
这给你带来了自信的希望
biblical counselor that is it's not your
圣经辅导员，这不是你的
responsibility to change others but it
除了它之外，有责任改变他人
is your responsibility to be faithful
忠诚是你的责任
and to live to the glory of God but you
除了你 ，要活出上帝的荣耀
need to live to the glory of God be
需要活出上帝的荣耀
faithful what's the definition of a
忠实的是什么的定义
successful counselor speak the truth in
成功的辅导员说实话
love in the power of the Spirit and
爱在圣灵的力量和
leave the results up to God because you
离开结果过神来，因为你
cannot change others ezekiel makes that
不能改变别人以西结的那个
very clear one man dies for his sin his
非常清楚一个人为他的罪而死
son dies for his sin father doesn't die
儿子为他的罪而死，父亲不死
for the sins of the son the son doesn't
对于儿子的罪的儿子不
die for the sins of the father and you
死于父亲和你 的罪
cannot change hearts only God if I'd
如果我不能改变心灵只有上帝
been more persuasive did you pray yes
被更有说服力你祈祷是
did you ask God to give you wisdom yes
你有没有请求上帝给你智慧
did you ask the power of the Holy Spirit
你问过圣灵的力量吗？
to work in you yes did you speak the
在你工作是的，你说的是
word yes you can't change hearts God
是的，你不能改变上帝的心
sends forth his word and Pharaoh's heart
发出他的话和法老的心
gets hard as a rock
变得像石头一样坚硬
God sends forth his brief word believe
上帝发出他简短的话语相信
on the Lord Jesus Christ and thou shalt
在主耶稣基督身上，你要
be saved in your house and the
被保存在你的房子里
Philippian jailer gets saved God does
腓立比的狱卒得救了上帝
his work you're not responsible for
他的工作你不负责任
their actions that's very clear in that
他们的行动是在说的 很清楚
tech you need to study it on your own
技术，你需要自己研究它
check me out
对我进行检查
Pia Berean God visits the effects of sin
Pia Berean上帝访问了罪的影响
on following generations will your kids
下一代将是你的孩子
learn your sins yep
了解你的罪过是的
they will learn to say Fiddlesticks the
他们会学会说Fiddlesticks
exact same way you say it now they won't
完全相同的方式你现在说他们不会
say the f-word if you're a Christian you
如果你是基督徒，请说出f字
use Christian curse words like
用基督教的诅咒之词
fiddlesticks
木竿
but you say it with the same vehemence
但你用同样的激情说出来
and you say it with the same intonation
你用相同的语调说出来
and you say it with the same attitude of
你用同样的态度说出来
heart and it is unwholesome words and it
心脏，它是不健康的话语和它
is sin and your kids will learn to say
是罪，你的孩子会学会说
it just like you do you lie they learn
它就像你在撒谎他们学习
to lie you treat your mom like you treat
撒谎你像对待你一样对待你的妈妈
your wife like dirt they'll treat their
你的妻子喜欢他们会对待他们的污垢
mom like dirt you know the sins get
妈妈喜欢你知道罪恶的污垢
visited because we teach our children to
因为我们教孩子们去参观
sin but if you deal with your sin they
罪， 但如果你处理你的罪，他们
will learn from you how to deal with sin
将向你学习如何处理罪恶
your job is to live for the glory of God
你的工作就是为了上帝的荣耀而活
whether then you eat or drink or whether
无论你是吃还是喝，或者是否
whatever you do do it all for the glory
无论你做什么都为了荣耀而做
of God
上帝
that's what you need to do and walk with
这就是你需要做的事情并与之同行
Him and trust him in the midst of those
他并相信他在那些之中
things and remember this in this last
事情， 并记住这最后
point your trials and your tests are
点你的试验和您的测试
designed for your good and your growth
专为您的利益和成长而设计
we've talked about this overall but
我们已经谈过这个整体，但
Romans 8:28 all things work for good the
罗马书8:28万事都工作
evil that you meant toward me God meant
你对我意味着什么邪恶上帝的意思
for good and so in James 1:2 - for those
为好，所以在雅各书1：2 -为那些
trials come and they're meant to produce
试验来了，他们打算生产
growth in you so you have hope no matter
在你身上成长，无论如何你都有希望
what it is Oh God meant this for good
它是什么哦上帝意味着好
God means this for my growth God intends
上帝意味着上帝的意图
for me to grow through this and you and
让我通过这个和你和你成长
I need to grow in hope because of that
我需要因为这个希望长大
we need to work for the glory of God
我们需要为上帝的荣耀而努力
whatever we do whether we eat or whether
无论我们做什么，无论我们吃或是否
we drink that gets it down to right
我们喝酒让它变得正确
pretty minimal stuff you know okay is
相当简单的东西， 你知道没关系
this fourth cookie for the glory of God
这第四个饼干是为了荣耀上帝
or should I switch to some trail mix
或者我应该切换到一些混合
maybe you're going to snack time so I
也许你会去吃零食时间，所以我
thought I'd bring in a little conviction
以为我会带来一点信念
before you go alright the hope is that
在你顺利之前，希望就是这样
you can do all things through Christ who
你可以通过基督来做所有事情
strengthens you
加强你
you
您